最重要的讯息之一
One of the most important messages
我想在这门课程中遇到的
that I want to get across in this course
是你不必记住
is that you do not have to memorize
每一个 CSS 属性，
every single CSS property that there is,
或者您在本课程中学到的知识。
or that you learn in this course.
而且你实际上可以开始编写自己的 CSS，
And also that you can actually start writing your own CSS,
即使你还不知道一切。
even when you don't know everything yet.
所以对于像你这样的初学者，
So for beginners, like you,
了解事实非常重要
it's really important to be aware of the fact
什么都不知道也没关系
that it is okay not to know everything
你可以随时谷歌
and that you can always Google
当你什么都不知道的时候
when you don't know anything
或阅读文档。
or read the documentation.
所以在这次讲座中，
And so in this lecture,
我想快速向您展示一些技巧
I want to quickly show you some techniques
我用谷歌搜索我不知道的东西，
that I use to Google stuff that I don't know,
以及如何阅读文档
and also how to read documentation
为了了解有关财产的知识
in order to learn something about a property
你还不知道的，
that you don't know yet,
或者您不记得如何使用。
or that you don't remember how exactly to use.
让我们从一个假设开始，
And let's start with a hypothetical,
但现实世界的场景。
but real world scenario.
所以让我们假设你在你的网页上建立了一个论坛
So let's imagine that you built a forum on your webpage
那个论坛有一个按钮，
and that forum has a button,
但现在你不记得如何实际添加
but now you don't remember how you can actually add
就像那个鼠标光标到按钮一样。
like that mouse cursor to the button.
因此，当您的用户悬停按钮时，
So when your users hover the button,
你希望它看起来像这样。
you want it to look something like this.
所以随着这个光标在这里发生，
So with this cursor here happening,
但同样，
but again,
你不记得该怎么做。
you don't remember how to do that.
但又一次，
But again,
你可能不记得如何实际做到这一点。
you might not remember how to actually do that.
这真的完全没有问题。
And this is really no problem at all.
所以你总是可以谷歌一些东西
So you can always Google something
如果你不知道怎么做
if you don't know how to do it
并阅读文档。
and read the documentation as well.
所以在这种情况下，这就是我要做的。
So in this case, this is what I would do.
所以我会谷歌CSS，
So I would Google CSS,
所以我总是使用的第一个词
and so the first word that I always use
当我搜索与 CSS 相关的东西时，就是 CSS。
when I'm searching something related to CSS is CSS.
然后让我们说，
And then let's say,
要添加的 CSS 属性
CSS property to add
鼠标光标到按钮。
a mouse cursor to button.
所以这基本上就是你想要实现的目标，对吧？
So this is basically what you want to achieve, right?
然后在搜索结果中，
And then in the search results,
通常您想查找 stackoverflow.com。
usually you want to look for stackoverflow.com.
所以stackoverflow基本上是一个网站
So stackoverflow is basically a website
数百万用户在哪里发布了数十
where millions of users have posted tens
或者数亿个问题
or maybe hundreds of millions of questions
关于各种编程。
about all kinds of programming.
这包括 CSS。
And that includes CSS.
所以这个 W3schools 通常不是一个很好的参考。
So this W3schools is usually not a good reference.
所以不要用那个。
So don't use that.
然后还有CSS-Tricks，也很不错。
Then there's also CSS-Tricks, which is also very good.
下面是 developer.mozilla.org，
And down here there is developer.mozilla.org,
这实际上是 MDN 文档，
which is actually the MDN documentation,
我们将在一分钟内查看。
which we will check out also in a minute.
但现在我感兴趣的是stackoverflow，
But for now I'm interested in here is stackoverflow,
这又像一个问答网站
which again is like a Q&amp;A site
人们可以在哪里提问
where people can ask questions
然后其他用户帮助他们。
and then other users help them.
所以这里我们有一个问题，
So here we have a question,
"如何将光标变成手
"How to change the cursor into a hand
当用户将鼠标悬停在列表项上时？”
when a user hovers over a list item?"
现在你对列表项并不真正感兴趣，
Now you are not really interested in the list item,
但剩下的问题
but the rest of the question
是你要找的东西，对吧？
is kind of what you're looking for, right?
因此，让我们尝试在这里查看我们的回复。
So let's try to take a look at our responses here.
这是最受欢迎的
And here is the most popular one
并且原始海报也被投票为正确的。
and which was also voted as correct by the original poster.
所以这里要做的就是基本上将游标集添加到指针
So here what to do is to basically add cursor set to pointer
到元素，应该得到那只手，对吗？
to the element, which should get that hand, right?
事实上，这实际上是解决方案。
And in fact that is actually the solution.
所以现在我们可以复制解决方案
So now we can just copy the solution
或者如果你认为这是一种不好的做法，
or if you think that is a bad practice,
那么你可以去你的按钮
well, then you can just go to your button
并手动编写。
and write it manually.
但重要的是现在你解决了你的问题
But what matters is that now you solved your problem
现在只需通过谷歌搜索，对吗？
simply by Googling it now, right?
再说一次，不要因为不得不谷歌而感到难过
So again, don't feel bad for having to Google
当你什么都不知道的时候。
when you don't know anything.
我每天都这样做。
I do that every single day.
所以真正的开发人员永远不会知道一切。
So really developers never know everything.
我们只知道有些东西存在
We just know that something exists
我们也知道如何查找它。
and we also know how to then look it up.
所以你当然需要了解基础知识
So of course you need to know the fundamentals
关于 CSS 的实际工作原理。
about how CSS actually works.
但同样，您不需要记住每一个属性。
But again, you don't need to memorize every single property.
你只需要知道
You just need to know
可以将鼠标光标添加到按钮，
that it is possible to add a mouse cursor to a button,
但你不必总是知道如何做到这一点。
but you don't have to always know how exactly to do that.
好的。
Okay.
现在让我们试试另一个例子。
And now let's try another example.
并返回到我们的页面，
And returning actually here to our page,
假设我们想要将所有这些链接居中
let's imagine that we wanted to center all of these links
导航里面。
inside of the navigation.
所以这里有导航，这里有这些链接
So here we have the navigation and here we have these links
所以我们想把它们放在中心。
and so we want to center them.
因此，让我们尝试自己做这件事。
So let's try to do that on our own.
第一种方法可能是选择
And the first approach might be to select
这些锚元素
these anchor elements
并将文本对齐设置为中心，对吗？
and set the text-align to center, right?
所以我很确定我们在某个地方选择了它们
So I'm pretty sure we selected them somewhere
他们实际上在这里。
and here they are actually.
所以让我们做我刚才解释的事情。
And so let's do what I just explained.
因此，让我们尝试 text-align 并设置为中心。
So let's try text-align and set to center.
让我们拯救它。
Let's give it a save.
也许我必须手动重新加载。
Maybe I have to reload manually.
好的。
Okay.
但现在你看到什么都没有改变。
But now you see that nothing changed.
所以让我们检查一下。
So let's inspect this.
我们需要更多的空间。
And we'll need some more space here.
好的。
All right.
所以选择它们，
And so selecting them,
当然我们可以看到 text-align, center 确实设置了，
of course we can see the text-align, center is indeed set,
但仍然没有任何反应。
but still nothing happens.
好的。
All right.
但是，如果我们考虑到这一点，
However, if we think about this,
这实际上是有道理的
this actually makes sense
因为文本行确实
because texts line does
基本上是使元素内部的一些文本居中。
is to basically center some text inside of an element.
现在这里的这些元素是内联元素。
Now these elements here are inline elements.
因此他们占据的唯一空间
And therefore the only space that they occupy
正是内容需要的空间，对吧？
is exactly the space that the content needs, right?
所以这些元素的宽度
And so the width of these elements
完全符合内容所需的宽度。
is exactly as wide as it needs to be to fit the content.
因此不可能
Therefore it is not possible
将其中的任何东西居中
to center anything inside of them
因为根本没有空白
because there's simply no empty space
元素可以在其中居中。
inside of which the element could be centered.
好的。
Okay.
所以得出了这个结论，
So having arrived at that conclusion,
也许现在你不知道如何真正解决问题
maybe now you don't know how to actually solve the problem
因为您仍然希望所有这些链接都集中在此处。
because you still want all these links centered here.
所以让我们再次尝试谷歌。
So let's try to Google that once again.
让我们说 CSS 如何使锚元素居中。
Let's say CSS how to center anchor elements.
好的。
Okay.
而现在，
And now again,
你想寻找stackoverflow.com
you want to be looking for stackoverflow.com
而这个看起来正是我们正在寻找的。
and this one looks exactly what we are looking for.
那么如何在 CSS 中将锚元素居中，
So how do I center an anchor element in CSS,
并且很多次
and many times
您实际上需要提出各种问题
you actually need to open up various questions
因为并不总是他们的问题
because not always their question
和你的完全一样。
is exactly the same as yours.
现在，在这种情况下，
Now, in this case,
我们实际上在这里有正确的解决方案。
we actually have the correct solution right here.
所以他们说的是，
So what they say is,
"添加 text-align CSS 属性
"Add the text- align CSS property
到它的父样式属性。”
to its parent style attribute."
嗯，这部分的style属性
Well, this part of the style attribute
并不真正相关
is not really relevant
因为记住，我告诉过你不要使用这样的风格。
because remember, I told you not to use style like this.
对。
Right.
而是使用一个类，
But instead using a class,
这也不是很重要。
and that is also not really important.
重要的是我们需要的是这个。
What matters is that what we need is this.
所以我们需要将文本对齐中心设置为父级。
So we need text-align center set to the parent.
好的。
All right.
那么让我们把它放到我们的代码中。
So let's then put that into our code.
所以我们不希望这里出现，
And so we want this not here,
但我们希望它在资产净值中。
but we want it in the NAV.
所以让我们去寻找资产净值。
So let's go look for the NAV.
它应该在顶部的某个地方。
It should be somewhere at the top.
这里是。
Here it is.
现在 text-align 设置为居中。
And now text-align set to center.
现在我们开始。
And here we go.
所以现在这些元素实际上是居中的
So now these elements are actually centered
在父容器内。
inside of the parent container.
好的。
Okay.
在这种情况下，这有效
And in this case, this works
因为这些元素是内联元素
because these elements are inline elements
或者实际上在这种情况下，内联块。
or actually in this case, inline-blocks.
但重要的是他们不占用
But what matters is they do not occupy
父级的整个宽度。
the entire width of the parent.
所以当我们想把一堆这样的元素居中时，
And so when we want to center a bunch of elements like this,
无论是 inline 还是 inline-block 元素，
no matter if inline or inline-block elements,
那么我们需要做的就是
then all we need to do
就是添加text-align center属性
is to add the text-align center property
在父元素上。
on the parent element.
好的。
Okay.
现在也许你想多学一点
Now maybe you wanted to learn a little bit more
关于这个属性。
about this property.
所以现在让我们使用 MDN 文档。
And so let's now use the MDN documentation.
现在这不是官方文档，
Now this is not an official documentation,
但它仍然是大多数开发人员使用的
but it's still what most developers use
查找 CSS 属性。
to look up CSS properties.
所以我们先写MDN然后写CSS，
So we write MDN then CSS,
因为在 MDN 上有很多不同的语言。
because on MDN, there are many different languages.
然后让我们说文本对齐。
And then let's say text-align.
然后在这里，
And then here,
第一个结果已经是我们正在寻找的。
the first result is already what we're looking for.
所以 developer.mozilla.org。
So developer.mozilla.org.
所以在这里，基本上有一个描述
And so here, there is basically a description
还有一些关于不同值的演示
and also some demos about different values
对于这个属性。
for this property.
所以 text-align CSS 属性
So the text-align CSS property
设置内容的水平对齐方式
sets the horizontal alignment of the content
在块元素或表格单元框中。
inside a block element or table-cell box.
好的。
Okay.
这正是我们所做的。
And so that's exactly what we did.
所以我们在这里设置，
So we set it here,
块元素上的文本对齐中心，对。
text-align center on a block element, right.
之前我们尝试将它设置在一个内联块元素上
And previously we tried to set it on an inline block element
它没有做任何事情。
and there it didn't do anything.
所以我们也可以得到
And so we could also have gotten that
这里来自文档。
here from the documentation.
然后在这里我们可以点击一些不同的演示。
Then here we can click on some different demos.
所以当然是左，右，中，甚至还有理由。
So of course left, right, center and there's even justify.
那么这里是存在的所有不同的值。
Then here are all the different values that exist.
然后这里有一堆，
And then here's a bunch of,
甚至更多你可能不需要的东西。
even more stuff that you probably don't even need.
所以还有很多例子，这个也很重要。
So a lot of more examples, and this one is also important.
好吧，在这种情况下，
Well, not in this case,
但在一些更现代的房产中。
but in some more modern properties.
在这里我们可以看到浏览器的兼容性
Here we can see the browser compatibility
这个特定的 CSS 属性。
of this specific CSS property.
所以在这种情况下，它不是那么相关，
So in this case, it's not that relevant,
但有时您可能也想检查一下。
but sometimes you might want to check that out as well.
现在另一个，例如，
NoW another one, for example,
我们可以检查边界
we can check for border
因为这个有点复杂。
because this one is a little bit complex.
假设你想设置一个边界，
And so let's say you want to set a border,
例如，虚线或波浪形边框，
for example, a dotted one or a wavy border,
但你不记得确切的语法。
but you don't remember exactly the syntax.
好的。
All right.
所以这里你再举几个例子，
So here you have a couple of examples once again,
您可以单击它们并检查它们。
and you can click them and check them out.
正如我之前提到的，在这里你还可以学习，
And here you can also learn, as I mentioned before,
该边框实际上是一个速记属性
that border is actually a shorthand property
用于边框宽度、样式和颜色。
for the border width, style and color.
然后在这里，你有一堆例子
And then here again, you have a bunch of examples
是的，对于您想要的所有属性，
and yeah, for all the properties that you want,
您可以查看文档以准确了解
you can check out the documentation to learn exactly
您可以赋予他们什么价值以及他们如何工作。
what values you can give to them and how they work.
好的。
Okay.
我认为，
And I think with this,
我向你展示了足够多的东西，所以你可以靠自己
I showed you enough so that you can on your own
现在尝试谷歌一些你可能有的问题，
now try to Google some questions that you might have,
并阅读有关某些属性的文档
and also read documentation about some properties
你可能不知道它们是如何工作的。
that you might not know exactly how they work.
这是一项非常重要的开发人员技能
And this is a really important developer skill
当你开始成为一名 CSS 人员时你需要学习的东西
that you need to learn as you start becoming a CSS
以及 HTML 开发人员。
and also HTML developer.